Guide to the James Harvey Rogers Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- ADDRESSES, ESSAYS, AND REVIEWS, 1915-1939; Series II; 2.5 linear feet (6 boxes)
  - "Constructive Money and Foreign Trade Cycles", 1932 August (Box 28, Folder 417)
  - "Tariffs and Other Trade Restrictions on International Policy", 1932 October (Box 28, Folder 418)
  - "Vilfredo Pareto", 1932 October (Box 28, Folder 419)
  - "Inflation and Deflation", 1932 October (Box 28, Folder 420)
  - "Muddling with Money", 1932 November (Box 28, Folder 421)
  - "Federal Reserve Policy in World Monetary Chaos", 1932 December (Box 28, Folder 422)
  - "On British-American War Debt Negotiations", 1933 January (Box 28, Folder 423)
  - Testimony on economic problems and their cure, 1933 March (Box 28, Folder 424)
  - "The Banking Crisis of March 1933", 1933 March (Box 28, Folder 425)
  - "On Getting Adequate Funds to Spenders", 1933 March (Box 28, Folder 426)
  - "Sound Inflation", 1933 (Box 28, Folder 427)
  - Calm reaction to end of gold standard, 1933 April (Box 28, Folder 428)
  - Address on devalorization of the dollar, 1933 April (Box 28, Folder 429)
  - "The Breakdown of the Federal Reserve Credit Expansion Policy", 1933 May (Box 28, Folder 430)
  - "America's Position in the World Economic Conference", 1933 May (Box 28, Folder 431-432)
  - "Monetary Aspects of Economic Conference", 1933 May (Box 28, Folder 433)
  - "The Position of the U.S. in the World Economic Conference", 1933 June (Box 28, Folder 434)
  - "Forecasts for Next Year", 1933 June (Box 28, Folder 435)
  - On O.M.W. Sprague's resignation, 1933 November (Box 28, Folder 436)
  - "Talk before N.Y. Press", 1933 November (Box 28, Folder 437)
  - "The Economics of the President's Money Policy and Inflation", 1933 December (Box 28, Folder 438)
  - "Some Economic Aspects of the President's Money Policy:" testimony, 1934 January (Box 28, Folder 439)
  - "Introduction" for H. Puxley's A Critique of the Gold Standard, 1934 March (Box 28, Folder 440)
  - "Valentine Resolutions", 1935 February (Box 28, Folder 441)
  - "Notes on Conversation with Sir Henry Strakosh", 1935 May (Box 28, Folder 442)
  - "Monetary Policies and their Effects upon Prosperity in Various Countries", 1935 July (Box 28, Folder 443)
  - "A Supreme Court of Money", 1935 July (Box 28, Folder 444)
  - Geneva lectures, 1935 August (Box 28, Folder 445)
  - "Some Economic Activities of the League", 1935 November (Box 28, Folder 446)
  - "The Problem of Currency Stabilization", 1935 November (Box 28, Folder 447-448)
  - "The Prospect of Inflation", 1936 January (Box 28, Folder 449)
  - "Observable World Trends", 1936 February (Box 28, Folder 450)
  - "The Problem of Currency Stabilization", 1936 February (Box 28, Folder 451)
  - "The Prospect of Inflation in the U.S.", 1936 February (Box 28, Folder 452-453)
  - "The Problem of International Monetary Stabilization", 1936 April (Box 28, Folder 454)
  - Remarks in honor of Freud, 1936 April (Box 29, Folder 455)
  - "Monetary Management on Gold", 1936 May (Box 29, Folder 456)
  - Press statement on stabilization hopes, 1936 September (Box 29, Folder 457)
  - "The Monetary Situation in the U.S.", 1936 November (Box 29, Folder 458)
  - "The International Monetary Situation", 1936 November (Box 29, Folder 459-460)
  - "Monetary Policies and their Effects on Agriculture, 1936 December (Box 29, Folder 461)
  - "Suggestion to Mr Keynes", 1936 (Box 29, Folder 462)
  - "The Movement Toward Currency Stabilization", 1937 January (Box 29, Folder 463)
  - "The International Monetary Situation", 1937 January (Box 29, Folder 464-465)
  - Talk to former University of Missouri students, 1937 May (Box 29, Folder 466)
  - "The Threat of Inflation", 1937 May (Box 29, Folder 467)
  - Address at journalism banquet at University of Missouri, 1937 May (Box 29, Folder 468)
  - "Inflation Possibilities on Present Monetary Base", 1937 May (Box 29, Folder 469)
  - "Some Quantitative Aspects of Jun Inflation", 1937 June (Box 29, Folder 470)
  - "Some Lessons of Recent Monetary Policy in the U.S.", 1937 July (Box 29, Folder 471)
  - "The Threat of Inflation", 1937 July (Box 29, Folder 472)
  - "Memorandum..Inviting Cowles Commission to New Haven", 1937 July (Box 29, Folder 473)
  - "The Future of the Federal Budget", 1937 November (Box 29, Folder 474)
  - "Government Spending and the Capital Market", 1937 December (Box 29, Folder 475)
  - "Our Economic System as a Safeguard for an Enduring America", 1938 January (Box 29, Folder 476)
  - "Yale-Harvard-Princeton Conference on the Problem of the U.S. Government", 1938 February (Box 29, Folder 477)
  - Radio interview, 1938 March (Box 29, Folder 478)
  - "New Program of Government Spending and Credit Expansion", 1938 April (Box 29, Folder 479)
  - "If Not the American System, What?", 1938 April (Box 29, Folder 480)
  - Testimony: "National Council" Conference, 1938 May (Box 29, Folder 481)
  - Radio conversation, 1938 July (Box 29, Folder 482)
  - "Yale Press Publishes 'Capitalism in Crisis' by J.H. Rogers", 1938 October (Box 29, Folder 483)
  - "Is an Economic Plan for World Peace Possible?", 1938 December (Box 29, Folder 484)
  - "U.S. Can End Gold Problem by Winning South American Trade Through Loans", 1938 December (Box 29, Folder 485)
  - "Absorption of Credit vs. Absorption of Savings", 1938 December (Box 29, Folder 486)
  - "Forecast for 1939", 1938 (Box 29, Folder 487)
  - Radio converstion, 1939 January (Box 30, Folder 488)
  - "Why Capitalism is Threatened", 1939 March (Box 30, Folder 489)
  - "Is America Developing a Free Exchange Bloc?", 1939 (Box 30, Folder 490)
  - "The Race Between Credit Relief and Industrial Collapse", undated (Box 30, Folder 491)
  - "The Dawes Plan", undated (Box 30, Folder 492)
  - "Why Capitalism is Failing", undated (Box 30, Folder 493)
  - "Depression's Threat to Capitalism", undated (Box 30, Folder 494)
  - "How Funds are Absorbed by Purchasing", undated (Box 30, Folder 495)
  - "On Federal Reserve Policy", undated (Box 30, Folder 496)
  - "Economic Fetishism: Gold and Inflation", undated (Box 30, Folder 497)
  - "The Threat to the Gold Standard", undated (Box 30, Folder 498)
  - "The possible introduction of a tutorial system at Yale", undated (Box 30, Folder 499)
  - "Bachelor of Arts with Honors in Economics", undated (Box 30, Folder 500)
  - "The Businessman's Theological Theory of Depressions", undated (Box 30, Folder 501)
  - Fragments of essays, undated (Box 30, Folder 502)
  - Miscellaneous pieces, undated (Box 30, Folder 503)
- MANUSCRIPTS AND SPECIAL PROJECTS, 1915-1963, undated; Series III; 12 linear feet (29 boxes)
  This series is arranged in nineteen sections by topic or record type.
  - Manuscripts
    - America Weighs Her Gold, [ca. 1931] (Box 31, Folder 504-518)
    - America Weighs Her Gold, [ca. 1931] (Box 32, Folder 519-532)
    - America Weighs Her Gold, [ca. 1931] (Box 33, Folder 533-555)
    - Capitalism in Crisis, [ca. 1938] (Box 34, Folder 556-566)
    - Capitalism in Crisis, [ca. 1938] (Box 35, Folder 567-581)
    - Capitalism in Crisis, [ca. 1938] (Box 36, Folder 582-586)
    - Mind and Society, [ca. 1935] (Box 37, Folder 587-595)
    - Mind and Society, [ca. 1935] (Box 38, Folder 596-606)
    - Mind and Society, [ca. 1935] (Box 39, Folder 607-611)
    - Mind and Society, [ca. 1935] (Box 40, Folder 612)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 41, Folder 613-626)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 42, Folder 627-637)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 43, Folder 638-650)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 44, Folder 651-661)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 45, Folder 662-668)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 46, Folder 669-676)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 47, Folder 677-685)
    - Process of Inflation, [ca. 1929] (Box 48, Folder 686-696)
    - Stock Speculation, [ca. 1927] (Box 49, Folder 697-703)
  - Writings - Prospective Books
    - "The Third Approximation", [ca. 1926] (Box 49, Folder 704-707)
      General
      See also: box 76, folders 1012-1031
  - Butler Commission
    - Plans, 1933 January - November (Box 50, Folder 708)
    - Proposals, 1933 March (Box 50, Folder 709)
    - Reports, 1932 (Box 50, Folder 710)
    - Topical memoranda, 1933 (Box 50, Folder 711-712)
  - China
    - Diary, 1934 April - July (Box 50, Folder 713-715)
    - Miscellanea, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 716)
    - Notes, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 717)
    - Outlines, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 718)
    - Papers, 1934 (Box 50, Folder 719-720)
    - Papers, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 721)
    - Reports, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 722-723)
    - Research essays, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 724-725)
    - Research materials, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 726-727)
  - China, Japan
    - Conversations, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 728)
    - Diary, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 729)
  - China, Japan, India
    - Expense accounts, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 730)
  - China, Japan, Manchuria
    - Research essays, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 731)
  - China, India, Japan
    - Correspondence, 1934 March (Box 51, Folder 732)
    - Preparatory material, 1934 (Box 51, Folder 733)
  - Clippings
    - China, Japan, India: 1, 1934 May-October (Box 52, Folder 734)
    - China, Japan, India: 2, 1934 May-October (Box 52, Folder 735)
      See also: box 71, folders 959-960
    - U.S.A., 1933 July - 1935 June (Box 52, Folder 736-738)
  - Diary
    - 1915 April 8 - June 2, 1921 August - September, 1922 June 15 - July 26, 1929 July, 1933 September (Box 52, Folder 739-743)
  - Economic advisor to Franklin Delano Roosevelt
    - An International-Suggestion", undated (Box 52, Folder 744)
    - "Civil Works", 1933 November 7 (Box 52, Folder 745)
    - "Dangers of Present Position of Dollar", 1933 August 21 (Box 52, Folder 746)
    - Southern economic problems — cotton, 1933 August 24 (Box 52, Folder 747-748)
    - "Economic Effects in Sweden…" by Basil Dahl, 1933 December 1 (Box 52, Folder 749)
    - "Gold Buying Policy", 1933 November 15 (Box 52, Folder 750)
    - "How to Raise Prices", 1933 October 22 (Box 53, Folder 751)
    - "Insignificance of Gold Profit", 1933 (Box 53, Folder 752)
    - Material: Gold Reserve Act, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 753)
    - Memorandum: silver, 1934 (Box 53, Folder 754)
    - Miscellanea, undated (Box 53, Folder 755)
    - Monetary committee discussion, 1933 October 18 (Box 53, Folder 756)
    - Newspaper clippings: European trip, 1933 (Box 53, Folder 757)
    - Papers by J.H. Rogers, 1934 February - October (Box 53, Folder 758)
    - Policy proposals, 1933 August 21 (Box 53, Folder 759)
    - Reconstruction Finance Corporation Bill, undated (Box 53, Folder 760)
    - Reports, 1933-1934 (Box 53, Folder 761)
    - Reports and memoranda, 1933-1934, 1933 (Box 53, Folder 762-765)
    - Reports by C.W. Young Investment Co., 1933 November 23 (Box 53, Folder 766)
    - Research material: European trip, 1933 September (Box 53, Folder 767)
    - Research material: foreign relations, Italy, 1934 February 6 (Box 54, Folder 768)
    - Stabilization and managed currency, undated (Box 54, Folder 769)
    - Statement to World Economic Conference, 1933 July 12 - 21 (Box 54, Folder 770)
    - Suggestions, 1934 September 19 - 26 (Box 54, Folder 771)
    - "Two Guides…" by C.W. Young Investment, 1933 November 8 (Box 54, Folder 772)
  - Japan
    - Addresses, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 773)
    - Balance of trade data, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 774)
    - Notes on the economy, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 775)
    - Politics, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 776)
    - Public finance and debt, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 777)
    - Reports, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 778)
    - Reports: the budget, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 779)
    - Reports: the economy, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 780)
    - Reports: monetary policy, 1934 (Box 54, Folder 781)
    - Reports: budget, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 782)
    - World trade, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 783)
  - Japan and China
    - Press clippings, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 784)
  - India
    - Balance of trade, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 785)
    - Currency, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 786)
    - "Indo-Japanese Trade Agreement", 1934 (Box 55, Folder 787)
    - Public finance, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 788)
    - "Quantity of Silver in India", 1934 (Box 55, Folder 789)
    - Research material, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 790)
    - Research material on silver, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 791)
    - Research notes, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 792)
    - Silver, 1934 (Box 55, Folder 793)
  - Latin America
    - Research material, 1935-1936 (Box 56, Folder 794)
    - Research material; reports, 1936-1938 (Box 56, Folder 795)
  - League of Nations
    - Address: "Agricultural Protectionism…", 1935 May 2 (Box 56, Folder 796)
    - Economic Committee meetings, 1935 April - 1936 September (Box 56, Folder 797-799)
    - Papers, 1933-1936 (Box 56, Folder 800-804)
    - Report, 1933 November (Box 56, Folder 805)
    - "Talk before Economic Committee", 1936 September 9 (Box 56, Folder 806)
  - Mexico
    - Notes, 1937 (Box 56, Folder 807)
    - Reports, research material, 1936-1937 (Box 56, Folder 808)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Miscellanea, undated (Box 57, Folder 809)
    - Committee for the Nation, [ca. 1933] (Box 57, Folder 810)
    - Committee for the Nation: printed material, 1933-1936 (Box 57, Folder 811)
    - The Econometric Society, 1930-1933 (Box 57, Folder 812)
    - Fisher, Irving: festschrift, 1936 (Box 57, Folder 813)
    - Memorabilia, 1914-1937 (Box 57, Folder 814)
    - Papers: World War I, 1918 (Box 57, Folder 815)
    - Passports and visas, 1915-1934 (Box 57, Folder 816)
    - Personal bibliography, 1930-1936 (Box 57, Folder 817)
    - Personal notes, undated (Box 57, Folder 818)
    - Recollections of James Harvey Rogers, 1963, undated (Box 57, Folder 819)
    - University of Missouri papers, 1929 (Box 57, Folder 820)
    - Yale-Harvard-Princeton Conference, 1938 (Box 57, Folder 821)
  - Papers By Others - Miscellaneous, 1933-1934 (Box 58, Folder 822)
  - Research Materials
    - 1918-1935, undated (Box 58, Folder 823-831)
    - Research materials: Colombia, 1935-1936 (Box 58, Folder 832)
    - Research materials: Commerce Department reports, 1933-1934 (Box 58, Folder 833-835)
    - Research materials: foreign trade, 1934 (Box 59, Folder 836)
    - Research materials: government activities, 1936-1937 (Box 59, Folder 837)
    - Research materials: public debt bibliography, [ca. 1937] (Box 59, Folder 838)
    - Research materials: "Survey of Literature on Stabilization", 1935 (Box 59, Folder 839)
    - Research materials: U.S. monetary situation, [ca 1930s] (Box 59, Folder 840)
- TEACHING FILES, 1904-1939; Series IV; 4.5' (11 boxes)
  This series is arranged in four sections: Lecture Notes; Student Exams; Student Papers; and Yale University, Department of Economics.
  - Lecture Notes
    - Student
      - General: Card file, 1912-1916 (Box 60, Folder 840)
      - Arithmetic worksheets, undated (Box 61, Folder 841)
      - Banks and finance, 1912 (Box 61, Folder 842)
      - Courses at Chicago, 1912 (Box 61, Folder 843)
      - Dynamic Approach to Economic Theory, 1930 (Box 61, Folder 844)
      - Economic history, 1912-1913 (Box 61, Folder 845-847)
      - Financial history of the U.S., 1912-1913 (Box 61, Folder 848)
      - General economics, 1911 (Box 61, Folder 849)
      - History of economic thought, 1912-1913 (Box 61, Folder 850-852)
      - Junior essays, 1904-1905 (Box 61, Folder 853)
      - Labor problems, 1913 (Box 61, Folder 854)
      - Miscellaneous, 1912-1913 (Box 62, Folder 855)
      - Pareto, 1915 (Box 62, Folder 856)
      - Prices, 1913 (Box 62, Folder 857a)
      - Senior essays, 1905-1906 (Box 62, Folder 857b)
      - Thesis, M.A., "A History of Ancient Mathematics", 1907 (Box 62, Folder 858)
    - Teaching
      - Advanced monetary theory, 1923-1928 (Box 63, Folder 859)
      - Business cycles, [ca. 1920-1925] (Box 63, Folder 860-861)
      - CMP, 1954 (Box 63, Folder 862)
      - Corporate finance, 1919-1924 (Box 63, Folder 863-866)
      - Financial organization, 1938-1939 (Box 63, Folder 867)
      - Economic forces, 1930-1935 (Box 63, Folder 868-869)
      - Exams and miscellaneous, undated (Box 63, Folder 870)
      - Finance theory, 1921-1923 (Box 63, Folder 871)
      - General theory, [ca. 1919] (Box 64, Folder 872)
      - International finance, 1935 (Box 64, Folder 873)
      - Investments, 1920 (Box 64, Folder 874)
      - Investments and speculation, 1921-1928 (Box 64, Folder 875-876)
      - Miscellaneous, 1917-1930 (Box 64, Folder 877-883)
      - Monetary theory, 1932-1935 (Box 65, Folder 884-886)
      - Money and banking, 1919-1925 (Box 65, Folder 887-889)
      - Money, credit, and banking, 1920-1929 (Box 65, Folder 890-893)
      - Public revenues, 1917 (Box 65, Folder 894-895)
      - SM and BC, 1925-1926 (Box 65, Folder 896)
  - Student Exams
    - Yale - Commercial and investment banking, 1936 (Box 66, Folder 897)
    - Yale - Financial organization of society, 1938 (Box 66, Folder 898-899)
    - Yale - miscellaneous, 1933-1939 (Box 66, Folder 900)
  - Student Papers
    - Feuerlein, Willy, 1935 (Box 67, Folder 901-902)
      See also: box 68, folders 914-927
    - University of Missouri
      - Miscellaneous, 1927-1929 (Box 67, Folder 903)
      - "Current Monetary Problems", [ca. 1928] (Box 67, Folder 904)
      - "Foreign Exchange", 1925 (Box 67, Folder 905)
    - Yale University
      - "Epistomological Implications of Classical Value Theory", 1937 (Box 67, Folder 906)
      - Balance of payments, [ca. 1936] (Box 67, Folder 907)
      - Banking and monetary control, 1933-1936 (Box 67, Folder 908-909)
      - Business cycles, [ca. 1937] (Box 67, Folder 910-911)
      - Business cycles - honor's thesis, 1936 (Box 67, Folder 912)
      - "England and the Gold Standard", undated (Box 67, Folder 913)
      - International economics Australia, Canada, Colombia, Czechoslovakia, Germany, Japan, Italy, New Zealand, South Africa, Sweden, Switzerland, United States, and thesis prospecti, 1936 (Box 68, Folder 914-927)
      - Miscellaneous topics, [ca. 1935-1936, undated] (Box 69, Folder 928-929)
      - Monetary theory, 1933-1939 (Box 69, Folder 930-334)
      - Pareto, Undated, 1937 (Box 69, Folder 935-937)
      - Stabilization fund, undated (Box 69, Folder 938)
      - U.S. agriculture, undated (Box 69, Folder 939)
      - U.S. economic conditions, undated (Box 69, Folder 940a)
  - Yale University, Department of Economics
    - Course outline, 1937 (Box 70, Folder 940b-941)
    - Economics Ph.D. candidates, 1910-1933 (Box 70, Folder 942)
    - Examinations, 1934-1937 (Box 70, Folder 943)
    - Fellowships and scholarships, grades, 1931-1936 (Box 70, Folder 944)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1931-1937 (Box 70, Folder 945)
    - Miscellaneous, [ca. 1935] (Box 70, Folder 946-947)
- TOPICAL FILES, 1919-1940; Series V; 2.75 linear feet (7 boxes)
  This series is arranged in eight sections, alphabetically by record type.
  - Memorial Tribute, 1940 (Box 71, Folder 948)
  - News Analyses
    - "Federal Focus", [ca 1933-1935] (Box 71, Folder 949)
    - Fischer, Irving, 1933-1936 (Box 71, Folder 950)
    - 'Monthly Analysis', 1934 September (Box 71, Folder 951)
    - "Today's Ticker", 1936 (Box 71, Folder 952)
    - Whaley-Eaton, Keplinger Washington Letter, 1931-1934 (Box 71, Folder 953)
  - News Summaries
    - "The French Say", 1937 November (Box 71, Folder 954)
    - Pierson Digest, 1935 February - March (Box 71, Folder 955-956)
    - Treasury Department, 1937-1938 (Box 71, Folder 957)
  - Newspaper Clippings
    - Book reviews (of JHR's books), 1929-1938 (Box 71, Folder 958)
    - Chinese newspapers, 1934 April-July (Box 71, Folder 959-960)
      See also: box 52, folders 734-735
    - Miscellaneous, 1930-1938 (Box 71, Folder 961)
    - J.H. Rogers, 1929-1938 (Box 72, Folder 962-964)
  - Papers by Others
    - Banking crisis, 1933 (Box 72, Folder 965)
    - Anglo-Soviet affairs, 1919-1927 (Box 72, Folder 966)
    - Anti-trust, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 967)
    - Banking and prices, 1922-1937 (Box 72, Folder 968)
    - Emmett C. Baker, Inflation and Deflation Can Be and Should Be Eliminated, 1938 (Box 72, Folder 969)
    - Depression problems, [ca. 1934] (Box 72, Folder 970)
    - Depression prospects, 1933-1938 (Box 72, Folder 971-972)
    - Depression remedies, 1932-1935, undated (Box 73, Folder 973-975)
    - Econometrics, undated (Box 73, Folder 976)
    - Economic domestic policy, 1933-1934, undated (Box 73, Folder 977)
    - Farm Credit Administration, [ca. 1938] (Box 73, Folder 978)
    - Federal Reserve Board statement, 1936 (Box 73, Folder 979-980)
    - Gold, 1934, undated (Box 73, Folder 981)
    - Ray Ovid Hall. "Rejoinder to Dr. Amos E. Taylor", 1932 (Box 73, Folder 982)
    - Law and Society, undated (Box 73, Folder 983)
    - Miscellaneous topics, 1928-1938, undated (Box 74, Folder 984-987)
    - National agricultural program, 1936 (Box 74, Folder 988)
    - Production and prices, 1931-1932 (Box 74, Folder 989)
    - Reconstruction Finance Corporation, undated (Box 74, Folder 990)
    - Recovery, 1938 (Box 74, Folder 991)
    - Securities act, undated (Box 74, Folder 992)
    - Elegy: notes re: editions and ornaments, manuscripts and revisions, problems in poem and 20th century -- critical reactions to problems, 1936 (Box 74, Folder 993)
    - Per Jacobson, 1933. (Box 74, Folder 994)
    - John Pierson, thesis, undated (Box 74, Folder 995)
    - Vilfredo Pareto, 1935 (Box 74, Folder 996)
    - A.E. Wetti, "Economic Equilibrium", undated (Box 74, Folder 997)
  - Postcards, Photos, Press Releases
    - Picture postcards (China, Japan, Canada, Brazil, Europe), undated (Box 75, Folder 998)
    - Photographs, 1920-1934 (Box 75, Folder 999-1001)
    - White House press releases, 1933 (Box 75, Folder 1002-1003)
  - Research Material
    - Anglo-American relations, undated (Box 75, Folder 1004)
    - Balance of payments and war debts, undated (Box 75, Folder 1005)
    - Balance of trade and foreign trade, 1933-1934 (Box 75, Folder 1006)
    - Foreign trade, 1935 (Box 75, Folder 1007)
    - Foreign trade: Canada and U.S., 1935 (Box 75, Folder 1008)
    - Germany, 1936 (Box 75, Folder 1009)
    - Commission of Inquiry on National Policy in International Economic Relations, 1934 (Box 75, Folder 1010)
    - Monetary and other economic indices, 1930s: charts (Box 78)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research: report on financial research, 1936 (Box 78)
  - Writings - Prospective Books
    - "Economic Power": notes and drafts, [ca. 1935] (Box 76, Folder 1012-1013)
    - "Harnassing the World's Money", undated (Box 76, Folder 1014-1017)
    - "In Retrospectum Aurum", [ca. 1936] (Box 76, Folder 1018-1021)
    - "New Deal Accomplishments", 1936 (Box 77, Folder 1022-1029)
    - "Passing of Gold", [ca. 1933 (Box 77, Folder 1030)
    - "Silver Ring", undated (Box 77, Folder 1031)
    - "Third Approximation"
      See: box 49, folders 704-707
- Index to Selected Correspondents
  - Acheson, Dean Gooderham (1893-). TLS to James Harvey Rogers, no place., 1937 January 11 (Box 20)
  - Adelman, Adrien
    - 8 TLS to James Harvey Rogers, various places
      - 1938 March 1 (Box 22)
      - 1938 March 10 (Box 22)
      - 1938 March 29 (Box 22)
      - 1938 November 4 (Box 23)
      - 1938 November 29 (Box 23)
      - 1938 December 7 (Box 23)
      - 1938 December 13 (Box 23)
      - 1939 January 25 (Box 23)
  - Angell, James Rowland (1869-1949)
    - 2 TLS to James Harvey Rogers, no place
      - 1935 April 18 (Box 16)
      - 1935 November 7 (Box 17)
  - Angell, James Waterhouse (1989-)
    - 2 ALS and TLS to James Harvey Rogers, New York
      - 1928 May 8 (Box 5)
      - 1928 May 15 (Box 5)
  - Bakewell, Charles Montague (1867-1957). TLS to James Harvey Rogers,, Washington, D.C., 1933 March 2 (Box 11)
  - Balogh, Thomas (1905-)
    - 13 ALS, TLS and telegram to James Harvey Rogers, various places
      - 1933 September 11 (Box 12)
      - 1934 [Jan] undated (Box 13)